Ilayaraja Shanmugam

240 Natoma Station Drive, apt 315, Folsom, California - 95630 | 860-422-5814 | ilay2k12@gmail.com

Objective

Extensive knowledge in automated document design 14 years of experience in Customer Communication management and Enterprise Content Management providing end-to-end solution. Fulfilled role a Technical Architect for all phases of the Delivery Process including upgrades and conversions.

Education

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATIONS | AUGUST 2004

- · Major: Computer Science
- · College: Adhiparasakthi Engineering College, Madras University

Technical Skills

• HP Exstream 9.5, Design Manager, Design, Logic Designer, Live Editor 4.5, xPression 4.6, xDesign, xAdmin, xPresso for Word, xPresso for Dreamweaver, xPresso for Indesign, Documentum 6.7, xCP, Java.

Certifications

- EMC xPression Certification(E22-190)
- · EMC Proven Professional (Documentum) (E20-120)
- · Sun Certified Java Professional (SCJP)
- SaFE Agilist 4.5 Certification

Experience

TECHNICAL ARCHITECT | COGNIZANT | SEP 2017 - TILL DATE

- Design cohesive communication solutions of small, medium and large-scale applications and willing to take on increasingly complex tasks in putting together document composition, print and archive services for letters, statements, Bills, Checks in PDF, PS and AFP formats using Exstream Dialogue version 8 and 9.5.
- Delivered customized rules, formulas, functions in EXSTREAM DAILOGUE based on business requirements.
- Involved in all phases of Exstream development such Data variable mapping, creation of various objects, designing of the pages, development of the rules, Unit/Integration testing, packaging the application to create the PUB file and pushing the Exstream code to QA/UAT environments of Mainframe and scheduling.
- Extensive knowledge about Variables and Data Mapping of Print file, Columnar, Delimited, and XML data files
- · Well versed with the Interface between Dialogue and Mainframe environment and the corresponding file transfer method for Data, PUB, PDF, PS and AFP Files.
- · Review requirements with business partners, providing feedback and/or comments, and troubleshoot any implementation issues; consulting on Technical Builds.

• In depth knowledge of document compositions, style sheets, variables, tables, document flow. Monitor and troubleshoot observations or concerns related to dialogue development-to include researching issues/defects to determine root cause.

XPRESSION TECHNICAL ARCHITECT | COGNIZANT | FEB 2012 - SEP 2017

- Integration between GuideWire and xCP systems through xPression web services including document creation, edit document, approval and other processes.
- · Input file cleanse using spring.
- · Creation HTML templates using xPresso for Dreamweaver.
- · Schema creation, category, data source, data source group creation in xAdmin.
- · Output delivery configuration for email delivery to ET.
- · Integration between xPression and xCP.
- · Batch Process creation using xDashboard.
- · Automated Batch processing between xPression and xCP.
- · xPression upgrade from 4.2 to 4.6.
- · Creation of reports using Business Activity Monitor.
- Involved in all phases of xPression development such Data variable mapping, creation of various objects, designing of the pages, development of the rules, Unit/Integration testing, packaging the application to create the PDPX file and pushing the xPression code to QA/UAT environments.

TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST | COGNIZANT | DEC 2008 - FEB 2012

- · Creation forms using xDesign.
- · Process creation using process builder.
- · Configuration of Taskspace application.
- · Development using SBO.
- · Adaptor configuration and customization.
- · Customization using WDK and Webtop.
- · Creation of reports using Business Activity Monitor.

DEVELOPER | HCL | MAR 2005 - DEC 2008

- · Rendition server maintenance.
- · Index server maintenance.
- · Customization of WebTop using WDK.
- · Requirement gathering on the enhancements.
- · Trained offshore team on the system and client process specific SOPs
- · Lead offshore team
- · Client interaction and co-ordination with offshore.

Visa Validity

- · H1B valid till June 2019.
- Green card status i140 approved. Priority date June 2014.